[MIKASA gasps] It's him.
That was Eren's voice!
[EREN]
My name is Eren Jaeger.
I'm addressing my fellow
Subjects of Ymir.
Speaking to you directly through
the power of the Founder.
All the walls on
the island of Paradis
have crumbled to the ground,
and the legions of Titans buried
within have begun their march.
My only goal is to protect
the lives of the
people of Paradis,
the island where I was born.
Right now, the nations of
the world are united
in their desire to
exterminate my people,
and it won't end
with our island.
They won't be satisfied until
every last Subject
of Ymir is dead.
I won't let them have their way.
The Titans of the Walls
will continue their march
until every trace of life beyond
our shores is trampled flat
and the people of Paradis are
all that remains of humanity.
♪ Opening Song ♪
[ELDIANS gasp]
What the?
Wait, where did we
all go just now?
Mister Leonhart?
Are you alright over there?
[ANNIE'S FATHER]
Yes, but did you hear him?
The Titans from that island
are on their way to kill us all.
[GABI]
Falco! Where are you?
We're here!
If you can hear me,
say something!
Becoming one of the
Nine is a real ordeal.
It leaves you helpless.
It screws up your memories, too.
There's no way they
wouldn't have grabbed him.
But why? Who's "they"?
I'm gonna guess Jean and Conny
saw how everything went down
and realized Falco was far
too important to leave behind.
They'll bring him back
to the Scouts.
[REINER] They know he's
got one of the Nine.
There's no way they'd let him--
[REINER groans]
What's wrong, Reiner?
Did you use up all your power?
[REINER] Yeah. My armor came
undone right as the wall fell.
A chunk of it hit me dead-on.
[REINER]
I couldn't stop him.
Huh?
It's over.
Eren's about to
destroy the world.
South of here we have
airships ready to escape.
Find Pieck, or anyone who's
still alive and flee the island.
You have to go warn
Marley and the world.
Fast as you can.
What does it matter
if we warn them?
They have nowhere to run.
My mom and dad and Aunt Karina.
They're gonna die along with
everybody else in Marley.
That's right.
Then we need to
kill Eren and save them!
We can't do that.
The Founder's control
over all Titans
and Subjects of Ymir
is absolute.
There's no way
we can stop Eren now.
The war's been decided.
There's no winning.
But if you keep moving,
maybe you'll see the aftermath.
[Gasps] Wait, Reiner.
[GABI] No way am I
just letting this happen.
Hang on, Falco. I'm coming.
[JEAN]
It's over.
[JEAN] Maniac or not,
I never thought Eren would
slaughter everyone
who lives outside the walls.
But when he's done,
everyone who hates us
will be dead.
The entire outside world
was a threat to our existence,
and now it's going to be
trampled flat and left empty.
These people called us
"island devils."
Said we'd kill them all,
unless they killed us first.
We became what
they thought we were,
and we're doing what
they feared we'd do,
because we have to.
In the end, it's on them.
This is only happening because
the world picked
a fight and lost.
There wasn't anything that we
could have done
differently, was there?
[ARMIN]
But even so...
Eren is going too far.
He's committing genocide
against the world.
[JEAN]
Well, then. What do we do?
Should we stop him?
Think on it.
Eren tricked Zeke
and kept him from
castrating us all with
his euthanization plan.
And Historia could've
taken the Founder,
but Eren opposed that 'cause
it would've cost her life.
He did this for his friends.
Eren wants to protect us,
even if it means
killing everybody else
on the planet.
He's doing something
more horrible
than we could imagine,
for our sakes.
Because you're important to me.
More than anyone else.
[ALL gasp]
What was that?
Wait a sec. The Titans are
going after our soldiers?
Did all the Marleyan
troops get eaten?
But why? Eren's using
the Founder's power.
He should have total control
over all these Titans!
Who cares why?
They're eating us!
Let's go and help!
[MIKASA] Jean, wait!
What'll you do with the kid?
I don't know,
but when he turned,
I think he ate the Jaw Titan.
That means we can use him,
feed him to one of our guys
who Zeke transformed.
We can bring someone back.
If we find
Commander Pyxis, then--
[CONNY]
No. We save my mom.
Take him to Ragako
and feed him to her.
All right?
Wait a sec. Guys.
Zeke told us this kid was
one of Marley's
Warrior candidates,
and that Reiner and
the rest of his unit
all treat him like
their little brother.
The war is basically over now.
Marley is about
to be trampled flat,
which means Reiner
and the Cart have
nothing to fight for unless
we give them something.
If we kill their friend now,
we'll be offering
the two of them
a whole new reason to
keep coming after us,
and we get nothing
out of it. Please--
What? You think bringing
my mom back is "nothing"?
That's not what I meant to--
For four years,
I've had to watch her
lie helpless in
the ruins of my home.
Do you have any idea
what that's like?
You ate Bertholdt.
That's why you're
still with us, right?
Well, my mom can
be with us too, now!
--Don't you dare--
--[MIKASA] Conny!
[Gasps]
Stop!
Conny, wait!
[JEAN]
Too late!
Shit.
There's no walls to
keep the Titans off us now.
We're gonna have to
take all of them out.
[VOLUNTEER 81A]
It's just a matter of time now.
We gotta get out of here!
Yelena! It's not safe!
[YELENA]
Zeke summoned all these Titans.
Huh?
[YELENA]
So, why?
Why would he allow them
to come after us?
[CADETS scream]
They broke through!
It's over. We're dead.
Don't slow down!
Stick to the narrow alleyways!
[roars]
Kaya! Watch out!
--Kaya!
--We have to keep running!
No!
Please, no. Not again.
Where are you, Sasha?
Please don't let it eat me!
Kaya!
[Roars]
[KAYA screams]
[ALL gasp]
Kaya! Get up!
[Yells]
Sasha. You came.
[KAYA crying]
Weren't you going to evacuate
with the Warrior Unit?
What are you doing here?
I decided I couldn't
leave without Falco.
That's Ben, innit?
[SCOUT 81A] Hey! You guys
all right down there?
[SCOUT 81B] Did you kill
the Titan yourselves?
[SCOUT 81A]
What's that weapon you've got?
Did the girl fire it?
Hold on. Is she that
Marleyan infiltrator?
Answer him or I will fire.
No, she's not!
She's my sister and our family
runs the stables to the south!
Kaya.
And I was the one
who fired the shot!
I'm a former prisoner of war,
so I know how to use this thing!
We ain't any threat to y'all,
so how 'bout you
point those guns away
and help get us to safety?
Help, Mister Soldier!
[ALL yelling]
[GABI]
You guys...
[ARTUR] Please, just get us
somewhere we can lay low.
Easy, we'll get you out.
We can guide you
around the flames.
It'll be all right.
You and Ben are gonna
make it out of all this,
but for the time bein',
you're gonna have to
stick with us and
keep your head down.
Right.
[SCOUT 81A]
I have to ask.
Did all of you have
that daydream, too?
Yeah. Was it true about
the Titans in the walls
stompin' the whole world flat?
[SCOUT 81B]
Yep. Seems to be.
So, uh, why did you
cover for me?
I can't explain it. And you?
Why would you wanna save me?
You know, you could have died.
Not sure.
Earlier. I tried to
stab you in the neck.
Maybe I really am a devil.
[GABI]
No. The only devil here is me.
[Gasps]
[GABI] I've killed
so many people in my life
just because I wanted praise.
It's sick. It's the devil in me.
[NICOLO]
There's a devil in me, too.
[Gasps]
And in you, Kaya,
and in everyone else.
That's why our world's
the way it is.
There's a devil inside us all.
But if that's true,
then what do we do?
We get out of the forest.
Maybe we'll fail, but we
still have to keep trying.
[Screams] Help me!
[CADET 73C]
Surma!
[SURMA screaming]
You okay, Surma?
[KEITH] I taught you punks
a dozen ways to deal with Titans
and whimpering like infants
isn't one of 'em!
We've still got some old ODM
gear lying around, so suit up!
You wanna see
the other side of this?
Get off your sorry asses
and follow me!
Commandant Shadis,
you're alive!
Are there any more
survivors in there?
Gather at the top floor!
We need to draw
the Titans into a group
so we can hit them all at once!
Get all the Thunder
Spears up there, too!
Whatever you've got,
we'll make it work!
Don't let any of
the Titans wander off!
These are the people
you trained and fought with!
They need us to
put them to rest!
Now! All at once!
[JEAN]
Fire!
Here they come! Pull back!
[KEITH]
This way!
[CADETS]
Sir!
There's no need for
any of you to fight.
Just lead 'em to the fort!
[ARMIN gasps]
[ARMIN]
Commander Pyxis.
Let's go.
Commander, we would
never have been able to
make it this far without you.
[ARMIN] So, thank you,
and rest in peace.
[SCOUTS yell]
[LOUISE yells]
[JEAN] The fires have
mostly died down.
Marley's troops were
pretty much wiped out,
and the Pure Titans
are all gone.
For the moment, we're safe.
[ONYANKOPON]
I see.
If we're out of danger,
you've got time to
talk about the daydream.
What'd he say?
What's Eren trying to do?
We're watching him do it.
Is that so?
Then my homeland
is doomed as well.
[JAEGERIST 81A]
Floch! Are you okay?
Yeah, no thanks to the wall
crumbling under my feet.
Good job mopping up all
the Pure Titans for us, Jean.
You survived.
Damn. No need to sound
so excited about it.
You should know
I'm not ready to die just yet.
Not before I finally get to see
the rebirth of
the Eldian Empire.
[FLOCH]
Yelena. Gather the Volunteers.
You're all under arrest.
--[Gasps]
--Hey, what are you doing?
Glad you're here, Mister Braus.
Good to see you.
And I'm glad y'all
made it through okay.
Apologies for givin' you
even more to deal with.
[ARMIN gasps] It's you.
Why are you here?
Believe me.
I'm not gonna make
any more trouble.
I just want my friend back.
So please. Let Falco go.
[ARMIN gasps]
[GABI] I swear, you'll never
hear from either of us again!
[Gasps] Where is he?
What's wrong?
[GABI] So, his mom got
transformed into a Titan
and he's gonna have her
eat Falco? But why?
When Conny's mom got turned,
the limbs on her
Titan body were so weak
she couldn't even roll over.
We left her, and for four years,
Conny's been visiting her...
Wait, four years?
[GABI]
I'm so sorry.
[GABI] But still,
I can't let Falco die for it!
Why do this?
Can't Eren Jaeger
just use his power
to turn Conny's mother
back to normal?
They say that the
Founder's supposed to
be able to do anything, right?
I can't say for sure,
but if Eren could do that,
I think he would've done it
for our comrades
that Zeke turned into Titans,
instead of leaving them
for us to kill.
If you don't know for sure,
then why can't you
go and ask him?
Does every person
beyond the shores
of the island
really need to die?
He doesn't have to
go that far, does he?
Ask him why he doesn't just
destroy all the military bases!
Isn't that enough?
He had the power to
strip the Armor off Reiner!
Don't tell me he can't!
[Gasps]
Can you tell us
where Reiner is now?
[GABI]
What does it even matter?
He got hit by a chunk of the
wall and he's too hurt to move!
[ARMIN]
You're telling us that Reiner's
hardening came undone?
When? When did it happen?
He said it fell off him
as the walls were collapsing.
[ARMIN gasps]
Does that mean...
When he brought
the walls down.
He did it by breaking
all Titan hardening everywhere.
[ANNIE coughing]
♪ Ending Song ♪
[NARRATOR]
They were once friends,
and they were once enemies.
Time is set back in motion,
and with it comes change.
The time to choose has arrived.
Next episode: "Sunset."